Big O visualization, oh of G of N is the set of functions with the smaller or the same order of growth
as G of M.
For example, if we have all of and squared, this means it includes with one o of n o of analog and
that we have seen in the chart and before so analyzed the algorithm at a larger and a values of and
only what this means below and zero.
We don't care about the rate of growth.
For example, if we took all of one.
This means it's one hundred one thousand two hundred one twenty.
This group of numbers will be considered of one because we don't have any, and the largest thing here
is 1000, which is a constant and it is not multiplied by anything.
So it is off one.
Another example is all of n these these numbers, we have three and a plus 100, one hundred and two
and minus one and the city.
The largest order between these numbers is the N.
So this is the N.
This is one hundred and and the largest order is one.
So and about Iran, it is N.
It is denoted by all of.
And OK, now another example, oh, of and look at five and log n plus 100.
This is the first term second, third, one hundred and two and minus one, and the three three is a
constant.
This is the least one we have and we have and but we have here five and look and so four and look and
is greater than DN.
So it took of and look n and not NN.
OK.
So this is and look at.
I will show you at the end of this video, I read memorization for the chart and I will show you why
we are doing this.
And the proof of these calculations, all of and square.
So if we have numbers and we need to get the complexity of them and the highest degree of them, three
am plus 100 with Dell, now we have an 100 and we have an do and minus one we have.
And so we neglect this and we keep on that great test or as I told you, okay.
And square minus two, and so we have now and square.
So it is and square and now and square here alone.
So it is and square the greatest one among these is and square.
So we took it as its big of Nitesh.
OK, I need it from you to register down and to write down on your copy.
Book that oh, of an.
As a smaller than look and as smaller than of an as smaller than analog and smaller than and squared
smaller than due to power and smaller than and factory, so please write down one.
Oh, of an hour of one less than lug and less than and less than and lug and.
Less than.
And Square.
And less than two to power and and less than.
And factory.
OK.
This is that.
Target of big notation, big o notation.
And this is the that's what I need from you to understand and to memorize well because all of our complexity
works will be.